Hello there.
We will now focus on data storytelling.
Data storytelling is effectively communicating insights from a dataset using narratives and visualizations.
There are four aspects of great data storytelling.
The first is accurate and complete data.
This helps establish trust with your stakeholders.
The second is a good design that provides clarity and is consistent.
The third is context.
Context involves explaining goals and customizing the message based on the audience.
The final aspect is the narrative.
Any dashboard or report should explain the next steps or the call to action.
Let us look at the multiple hats you must wear to tell a great data story.
You have done an excellent job so far.
Now, it is time to put on a consultant's hat.
This involves communicating the insights you gleaned to Whiskique's management.
They are business users and immediately understand terms such as sales, profit, and expenses.
So, removing technical jargon such as table merges, data sources, or parameters will be best.
Your dashboard-style pages should attempt to answer questions such as:
How will this grow my sales or profit?
How will this strategy improve customer satisfaction?
How can I save on shipping costs?
Your deliverable will consist of three dashboard-style pages.
You will reuse many of the charts built in the previous exercises.
In the executive summary dashboard-style page, you will provide key KPIs such as sales and profit.
This dashboard will provide a high-level pulse of the business.
The shipping costs dashboard-style page will suggest multiple strategies to reduce shipping costs.
The growth opportunities dashboard-style page will provide specific
recommendations on how Whiskique can grow sales using cross-sell promotions.
Let us now start building your data story.